Downtown Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Business Records, 1925-1974, undated, Series 4:; (Boxes 60-94, OV 95, OV 96, OV 97; 34.5 linear ft.; Reels 5603-5636)
  - Gallery Stock, 1926-1974, undated, 4.2:
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1953 (Reel 5617 (Box 67), Frame 469-600)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1953 (Reel 5617 (Box 67), Frame 601-744)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1954 (Reel 5617 (Box 67), Frame 745-900)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1954 (Reel 5617 (Box 67), Frame 901-1007)
    - Purchase Slips, A-O, 1955 (Reel 5617 (Box 68), Frame 1008-1208)
    - Purchase Slips, P-Z, 1955 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 6-184)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1956 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 185-385)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1956 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 386-569)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1957 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 570-700)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1957 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 701-887)
    - Purchase Slips (A-O), 1958 (Reel 5618 (Box 68), Frame 888-1096)
    - Purchase Slips (P-Z) (1 of 2), 1958 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 6-125)
    - Purchase Slips (P-Z) (2 of 2), 1958 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 126-240)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1959 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 241-400)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1959 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 401-559)
    - Purchase Slips, 1960 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 560-657)
    - Purchase Slips, 1961 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 658-778)
    - Purchase Slips, 1962 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 779-940)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1963 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 941-1075)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1963 (Reel 5619 (Box 68), Frame 1076-1202)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1964 (Reel 5620 (Box 68), Frame 6-125)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1964 (Reel 5620 (Box 68), Frame 126-278)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1965 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 279-400)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1965 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 401-510)
    - Purchase Slips (1 of 2), 1966 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 511-650)
    - Purchase Slips (2 of 2), 1966 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 651-755)
    - Purchase Slips, 1967 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 756-957)
    - Purchase Slips, 1968 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 958-1026)
    - Purchase Slips, 1969 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 1027-1097)
    - Purchase Slips, 1970 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 1098-1114)
    - Purchase Slips, 1971 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 1115-1124)
    - Purchase Slips, 1972 (Reel 5620 (Hol 69), Frame 1125-1129)
  - Sales Records, Artwork, 1928-1972, undated, 4.3:
    Sales records for artwork (5 linear feet) consist mainly of sales slips which are carbon copies of sales receipts issued by the Downtown Gallery. Each sales slip records the date of sale, name and address of buyer, medium, artist, [stock] number, title, and price. Additional miscellanous sales records include sale, credit, and return forms issued by Downtown Gallery which indicate date, name and address of client, description of item returned, and amount of credit; and various other ledgers of credits and returns, consignments, and statistics.
    Sales receipt slips are arranged by receipt numbers which are roughly chronological. Sales slips are followed by miscellaneous sales records.
    - Sales Slips, 1928, undated (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 131-221)
    - Sales Slips, 1929 (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 6-130)
    - Sales Slips, 1930 (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 513-683)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1931 (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 684-884)
    - Sales Slips(2 of 2), 1931 (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 885-1065)
    - Sales Slips, Jan. 1932 (Reel 5621 (Box 70), Frame 1066-1098)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), Jan.-Dec. 1932 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 6-150)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), Jan.-Dec. 1932 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 151-289)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1933 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 290-400)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1933 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 401-531)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1934 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 532-732)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1934 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 733-809)
    - Sales Slips, 1935 (Reel 5622 (Box 70), Frame 810-1070)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1936 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 7-125)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1936 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 126-260)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1937 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 261-375)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1937 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 376-500)
    - Sales Slips, 1938 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 501-680)
    - Sales Slips, 1939 (Reel 5623 (Box 70), Frame 681-866)
    - Sales Slips, 1940 (Reel 5623 (Box 71), Frame 867-1020)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1941 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 6-125)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1941 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 126-252)
    - Sales Slips, 1942 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 253-431)
    - Sales Slips, 1943 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 432-590)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1944 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 591-700)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1944 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 701-822)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1945 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 823-950)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1945 (Reel 5624 (Box 71), Frame 951-1087)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1946 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 6-200)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1946 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 201-401)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1947 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 402-550)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1947 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 551-714)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1948 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 715-915)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1948 (Reel 5625 (Box 71), Frame 916-1070)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1949 (Reel 5626 (Box 71), Frame 6-150)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1949 (Reel 5626 (Box 71), Frame 151-318)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1950 (Reel 5626 (Box 71), Frame 319-475)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1950 (Reel 5626 (Box 72), Frame 476-658)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1951 (Reel 5626 (Box 72), Frame 659-859)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1951 (Reel 5626 (Box 72), Frame 860-1036)
    - Sales Slips, Jan.-March, 1952 (Reel 5626 (Box 72), Frame 1037-1159)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), April-Dec., 1952 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 6-200)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), April-Dec., 1952 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 201-365)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1953 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 366-566)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1953 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 567-757)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1954 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 758-958)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1954 (Reel 5627 (Box 72), Frame 959-1147)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1955 (Reel 5628 (Box 72), Frame 6-215)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1955 (Reel 5628 (Box 72), Frame 216-433)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1956 (Reel 5628 (Box 72), Frame 434-634)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1956 (Reel 5628 (Box 72), Frame 635-815)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 3), 1957 (Reel 5628 (Box 73), Frame 816-950)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 3), 1957 (Reel 5628 (Box 73), Frame 951-1075)
    - Sales Slips (3 of 3), 1957 (Reel 5628 (Box 73), Frame 1076-1212)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 3), 1958 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 6-130)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 3), 1958 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 131-300)
    - Sales Slips (3 of 3), 1958 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 301-461)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 5), 1959 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 462-510)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 5), 1959 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 511-611)
    - Sales Slips (3 of 5), 1959 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 612-712)
    - Sales Slips (4 of 5), 1959 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 713-813)
    - Sales Slips (5 of 5), 1959 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 814-1021)
    - Sales Slips, Jan.-April, 1960 (Reel 5629 (Box 73), Frame 1022-1184)
    - Sales Slips, May-Dec., 1960 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 6-226)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 3), 1961 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 227-400)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 3), 1961 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 401-550)
    - Sales Slips (3 of 3), 1961 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 551-692)
    - Sales Slips (1of 2), 1962 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 693-893)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1962 (Reel 5630 (Box 73), Frame 894-1067)
    - Sales Slips, Jan.-May, 1963 (Reel 5630 (Box 74), Frame 1068-1222)
    - Sales Slips, June-Dec., 1963 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 6-179)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1964 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 180-350)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1964 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 351-508)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1965 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 509-625)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1965 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 626-784)
    - Sales Slips (1 of 2), 1966 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 785-925)
    - Sales Slips (2 of 2), 1966 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 926-1056)
    - Sales Slips, Jan.-July, 1967 (Reel 5631 (Box 74), Frame 1057-1284)
    - Sales Slips, Aug.-Dec., 1967 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 6-48)
    - Sales Slips, 1968 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 49-177)
    - Sales Slips, 1969 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 178-300)
    - Sales Slips, 1970 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 301-337)
    - Sales Slips, 1971 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 338-348)
    - Sales Slips, 1972 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 349-354)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Sales/Credits and Returns, undated, 1930-1941 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 355-453)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Our Gallery, Inc., Purchase Journal, Returns and Credits, 1926-1928, 1927 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 454-567)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Journal, Return Sales, Sales Book, 1927-1930, 1927-1928, 1926-1928 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 568-691)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Sales Records, A-Z (by artist), 1951-1955 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 692-882)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Consigned Sales, Consigned Purchases and Consigned Sales, undated, 1947-1965, 1964-1972 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 883-1081)
    - Miscelleanous Sales Records, Sales Statistics, undated, 1926-1951 (Reel 5632 (Box 74), Frame 1082-1149)
  - Transit Records, 1929-1972, undated, 4.4:
    Transit records (6.5 linear feet) consist of receipts issued by the Downtown Gallery for outgoing consignments and artwork received and returned, and receipts issued to the Downtown Gallery. These records were not microfilmed because the more easily accessible correspondence duplicates most information about specific transactions, and the aggregate data presented in this subseries are thought to be of interest to a very limited number of researchers.
    Outgoing consignment records include forms indicating the name of recipient, date sent and returned, artists, and titles, prices, and stock numbers of works consigned. The majority of consignments were loans to exhibitions that were available for purchase.
    Consignment forms for each year are filed alphabetically by name of consignee, usually a museum, commercial gallery, or university.
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Consignments, Outgoing, 1929-1945 (Reel unfilmed (Box 75))
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Consignments, Outgoing, 1946-1958 (Reel unfilmed (Box 76))
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Consignments, Outgoing, 1959-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 77))
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Shipping Receipts, undated, 1933, 1941, 1945-1969 (Reel unfilmed (Box 78))
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Artwork Received/Returned, 1935-1971 (Reel unfilmed (Box 79))
    - Receipts Issued by Downtown Gallery, Delivery Receipts, undated, 1960-1971 (Reel unfilmed (Box 80))
    - Receipts Issued to Downtown Gallery, Shipping Receipts, undated, 1930, 1940-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 81))
    - Receipts Issued to Downtown Gallery, Loan Receipts, undated, 1929-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 81))
  - Financial Records, General, 1925-1972, undated, 4.5:
    General financial records (11.5 linear feet) were not microfilmed. This subseries contains thirty-five volumes of accounting records which consist of cashbooks, journals, and general ledgers; receipts and disbursements; accounts receivable; and accounts payable. In addition, there are paid bills, petty cash records, and miscellaneous accounting records. Banking records include canceled checks, check registers, and bank statements for several accounts. Tax records (federal, state, and local) relate to both personal and corporate returns, and include much supporting documentation. Supporting documentation for deductions excludes art-related items.
    - Cashbook and Journal,(Our Gallery, Inc.), 1925-1930 (Reel unfilmed (Box 82))
    - Purchases, Credits, Journal, 1928-1930 (Reel unfilmed (Box 82))
    - General Journal, 1930-1935 (Reel unfilmed (Box 82))
    - Journal and General Ledger, 1931-1940 (Reel unfilmed (Box 83))
    - Journal, 1946-1950 (Reel unfilmed (Box 83))
    - Receipts and Disbursements, 1929-1972, (18 vols.) (Reel unfilmed (Box 83))
    - Accounts Receivable, A-Z, 1926-1969, (6 vols.) (Reel unfilmed (Box 84))
    - Accounts Payable, 1926-1972, (5 vols.) (Reel unfilmed (Box 85))
    - Paid Bills, 1930-1973, undated, (1 of 4) (Reel unfilmed (Box 86))
    - Paid Bills, 1930-1973, undated, (2 of 4) (Reel unfilmed (Box 87))
    - Paid Bills, 1930-1973, undated, (3 of 4) (Reel unfilmed (Box 88))
    - Paid Bills, 1930-1973, undated, (4 of 4) (Reel unfilmed (Box 90))
    - Petty Cash Vouchers, 1935-1972, undated (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Petty Cash Ledger, 1967-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Miscellaneous Accounting Records, Summary Reports, 1927/28-1940, 1955-1956, 1962, 1966/67-1971/72 (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Miscellaneous Accounting Records, 1931-1941, 1967 (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Miscellaneous Accounting Records, Sales Commissions Paid, 1931-1951 (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Miscellaneous Accounting Records, Payroll Accounts, 1965-1969 (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Miscellaneous Accounting Records, Purchase Orders and Requisition Forms, 1931-1971, undated (Reel unfilmed (Box 91))
    - Canceled Checks, Downtown Gallery, Inc., 1963-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Canceled Checks, Edith G. Halpert, 1931, 1941-1942, 1956-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Canceled Checks, Estate of Edith G. Halpert, 1972-1973 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Canceled Checks, Edith G. Halpert Foundation, 1966-1969 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Canceled Checks, 32 East 51st Street Corporation, 1949-1952 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Check Registers, Estate of Edith G. Halpert, 1972-1973 (Reel unfilmed (Box 92))
    - Bank Statements, Downtown Gallery, Inc., 1964-1972 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Bank Statements, Edith G. Halpert, 1942, 1957-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Bank Statements, Edith G. Halpert Foundation, 1966-1969 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Passbooks, Downtown Gallery Artists Welfare Fund, 1952-1957 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Passbooks, Lawrence A. Allen (gallery employee), 1956-1960 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Loan and Mortgage Receipts, Berthe K. Goldsmith Loan, 1935-1937 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Loan and Mortgage Receipts, Chase National Bank Loan, 1941-1946 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Loan and Mortgage Receipts, 43 East 51st Street Mortgage, 1945-1946 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Corporate and Personal Returns, Federal, 1922-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Corporate and Personal Returns, New York State, 1921-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Corporate and Personal Returns, New York City, 1933-1969 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Supporting Documentation for Deductions, Employment Taxes, [undated, 1940s-1970s] (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Supporting Documentation for Deductions, Federal Taxes, 1957, 1967-1971 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Supporting Documentation for Deductions, New York State, 1962, 1965-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
    - Taxes, Supporting Documentation for Deductions, New York City, 1940, 1965-1970 (Reel unfilmed (Box 93))
  - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1926-1968, 4.6:
    Miscellaneous business records (2.5 linear feet) include lists of artwork, many unidentified, which come from a variety of sources and were compiled for various purposes; twenty small loose-leaf notebooks listing names and addresses of clients with dates, titles, and prices of purchases; mailing lists on 3 X 5 index cards; legal documents such as certificates of incorporation, name changes, agreements, contracts, bills of sale, summons, notices of hearings, and bylaws; minutes of a few sporadic meetings of Downtown Gallery artists between 1934 and 1952; insurance records, primarily relating to the American Folk Art Gallery; research files, including material about legal issues of concern to galleries; and architectural plans. Architectural records include various plans for the Corcoran Gallery of Art and the proposed Gallery of 20th Century Art, Halpert's gift to the Corcoran that never materialized. There are also groups of plans relating to the Downtown Gallery's last two locations at 32 East 51st Street and 425 Park Avenue in the Ritz Towers Concourse.
    Lists of artwork in private collections are arranged by name of collector; client lists and mailing lists are arranged alphabetically.
    - Lists of Artwork (1 of 4), undated, 1931-1960 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 7-207)
    - Lists of Artwork (2 of 4), undated, 1931-1960 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 208-435)
    - Lists of Artwork (3 of 4), undated, 1931-1960 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 436-666)
    - Lists of Artwork (4 of 4), undated, 1931-1960 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 667-896)
    - Lists of Artwork in Private Collections, A-Z, undated, 1968 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 897-1035)
    - Lists of Photographs and Reproductions, undated, 1955-1969 (Reel 5633 (Box 93), Frame 1036-1086)
    - Prints: Shahn and Miscellaneous; Clients, Individuals, vol. 1: A-BA, 1958-1968, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 6-58)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 2: BE-BY, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 59-118)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 3: C, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 119-165)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 4: D-E, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 166-242)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 5: F, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 243-323)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 6: G, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 324-417)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 7: H-I, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 418-498)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 8: J-K, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 499-667)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 9: L-Mc, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 668-794)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 10: M, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 795-905)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 11: N, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 906-1028)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 12: O-Q, 1927-1975 (Reel 5634 (Box 94), Frame 1029-1065)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 13: R, 1927-1975 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 6-101)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 14: SA-SM, 1927-1975 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 102-166)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 15: SO-T, 1927-1975 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 167-248)
    - Clients, Individuals, vol. 16: U-Z, 1927-1975 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 249-292)
    - Clients, Institutions and Businesses, vol. 17: A-F, 1933-1969 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 293-463)
    - Clients, Institutions and Businesses, vol. 18: G-M, 1933-1969 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 464-626)
    - Clients, Institutions and Businesses, vol. 19: N-S, 1933-1969 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 627-704)
    - Clients, Institutions and Businesses, vol. 20: T-Z, 1933-1969 (Reel 5635 (Box 94), Frame 705-773)
    - Mailing Lists, Clients, Prospects, undated (Reel unfilmed (Box 94))
    - Mailing Lists: Museums, Galleries and Universities; Publicity; Newspapers; Free-Lance; Radio/TV; Magazines; Artists, circa 1960s (Reel unfilmed (Box 94))
    - Legal Documents, Certificates of Incorporation, Name Changes, Bylaws, 1926-1969 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 774-859)
    - Legal Documents, American Folk Art Gallery Bylaws and Stock Certificates, 1931 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 860-883)
    - Legal Documents, Leases, Deeds, and Miscellaneous Property Records, 113 West 13th Street Corporation, 1932 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 884-888)
    - Legal Documents, Leases, Deeds, and Miscellaneous Property Records, 32 East 51st Street Corporation, 1943-1965 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 889-993)
    - Legal Documents, Leases, Deeds, and Miscellaneous Property Records, Ritz Tower, Inc., 465 Park Avenue, 1965-1967 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 994-1001)
    - Legal Documents, Miscellaneous, 1935-1968 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 1002-1036)
    - Minutes, Irregular Meetings of Downtown Gallery Artists, 1934-1952 (Reel 5635 (Hol 95), Frame 1037-1052)
    - Insurance Schedules, 1935-1941 (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 6-159)
    - Insurance, Miscellaneous Records, undated, 1955-1968 (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 160-203)
    - Research Files, Sample Gallery Contracts and Form Letters, undated (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 205-234)
    - Research Files, Information Regarding Tax Law and Corporate Gifts, undated, 1957 (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 235-254)
    - Research Files, New York State Legislation Regarding Artist/Dealer Relationships, undated, 1966-1970 (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 255-303)
    - Research Files, 19th-Century Copies of Massachusetts Revolutionary Military Records, 1896-1897 (Reel 5636 (Hol 95), Frame 304-309)
      (these may have accompanied folk art portraits, documenting the sitters)
    - Architectural Plans, Suggested Gallery Site Plan of Bowling Alley and Foundations, 1931 (Reel 5636 (OV 96), Frame 311-312)
    - Architectural Plans, Newtown, Conn., 1939, 1957 (Reel 5636 (OV 96), Frame 313-315)
    - Architectural Plans, Corcoran Gallery of Art, and Proposed Gallery of 20th-Century American Art, 1960-1965 (Reel 5636 (OV 96), Frame 316-327)
    - Architectural Plans, Nieman-Marcus, Floor Plans, 1965, undated (Reel 5636 (OV 96), Frame 328-330)
    - Architectural Plans, Gump's Gallery, Floor Plan, undated (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 331-332)
    - Architectural Plans, Converse Art Gallery, Floor Plan, undated (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 333-334)
    - Architectural Plans, 525 William Penn Pl. Corporation, Pittsburgh, Pa. Main Lobby Elevations, 1950 (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 335-337)
    - Architectural Plans, United Nations, Elevation of North Delegates Lounge, undated (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 338-341)
      (attached transmittal slip indicates this blueprint was requested by Halpert in a letter to Glenn E. Burnett, Oct. 19, 1951)
    - Architectural Plans, Smithsonian Institution, Natural History Building, 1964 (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 342-344)
    - Architectural Plans, 32 East 51st Street, 1945-1950, undated (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 345-357)
    - Architectural Plans, 425 Park Avenue, Ritz Towers Concourse, circa 1965 (Reel 5636 (OV 97), Frame 358-361)
- Writings, 1917-1968, undated, Series 5:; (Box 98; 1 linear ft.; Reels 5636-5638)
  This series is organized into two subseries:
  5.1: Writings by Edith Gregor Halpert, 1917-1966, undated
  5.2: Writings by Others, circa 1920s-1968, undated
  - Writings by Edith Gregor Halpert, 1917-1966, undated, 5.1:
    Material found here includes Halpert's school notebook with notes from science class, P.S. 159, with color illustrations by Edith Fivisovitch; "Daily Thoughtlets" containing a notebook of poems by Edith Fibisovitch with typescript copies pasted on pages; short stories including manuscripts and fragments, most presumably written while Halpert was enrolled in writing courses at Columbia University; and various professional writings on American folk art such as drafts of texts for catalogs and possibly a book, articles, and notes.
    - School Notebook, undated (Reel 5636 (Box 98), Frame 364-420)
    - "Daily Thoughtlets," 1917 (Reel 5636 (Box 98), Frame 421-458)
    - Minutes of Inter-Departmental Meetings, S. W. Strauss and Co. (Edith Gregor Halpert, Secretary), 1923-1924 (Reel 5636 (Box 98), Frame 459-473)
    - Short Stories, undated, circa 1919-1920, 1924 (Reel 5636 (Box 98), Frame 474-561)
    - American Folk Art (1 of 2), undated (Reel 5636 (Box 98), Frame 562-699)